<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.5.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-08-29T19:03:42-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Miguel Tavares</title><subtitle>developer journal</subtitle><author><name>Miguel Tavares</name></author><entry><title type="html">Hello World!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/25/Hello-World.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World!" /><published>2017-08-25T08:15:16-03:00</published><updated>2017-08-25T08:15:16-03:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/25/Hello-World</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2017/08/25/Hello-World.html">&lt;p&gt;In the following posts I will try to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RVKofRN1dyI&quot;&gt;document&lt;/a&gt; my journey to becoming a developer. The main objective will be to give me a reference to what I learned and create an overview of the complete learning process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let me start at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;when-did-i-get-the-idea-to-become-a-developer&quot;&gt;When did I get the idea to become a developer?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past 5 years I have been working as a support agent for a software company called &lt;a href=&quot;http://appmachine.com&quot;&gt;AppMachine&lt;/a&gt;. Working in support gave me some insight in to solving technical issues and learning to test software and find bugs. Plus it also helped me build a thick skin when dealing with angry customers!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although I enjoy working in support minus the angry customers, I started to become more curious about programming. This lead to me search for online resources to learn how to code. These are the main sites that I have used so far to learn how to code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.freecodecamp.org/&quot;&gt;FreeCodeCamp&lt;/a&gt;: very easy to get started and I liked that from the beginning you learn by solving little code challenges. The difficulty level does ramp up significantly though. In particular the projects you have to do by yourself can be hard, because you go from a guided learning process to suddenly having to build something yourself from scratch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.codecademy.com/&quot;&gt;Codecademy&lt;/a&gt;: best online courses I found so far. Really nice layout and well thought out learning process. I did buy the Pro version to get access to the quizzes and projects. They are currently updating the courses, so some older courses are a bit outdated. This is where I first learned Ruby.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://udacity.com&quot;&gt;Udacity&lt;/a&gt;: not quite as good as Codecademy, but good to reference for specific doubts I had about HTML, CSS and JavaScript. The videos presentations are nice, but sometimes verge between funny and cringe.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theodinproject.com/&quot;&gt;The Odin Project&lt;/a&gt;: currently I am going through this open source curriculum. Nice thing about this course is that you’re not coding in a closed environment and are forced to learn development tools from the beginning, like the command line and Git. They also reference a lot of great online resources on each subject that I’m bookmarking for later use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s next?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The online courses really helped me make up my mind that this the path I want to pursue and gave me basic knowledge of the full development stack. Still I wanted something that would help me accelerate my learning. So after doing some research I decided…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…to join the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lewagon.com&quot;&gt;Le Wagon&lt;/a&gt; developer bootcamp!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be starting at the end of September in the Lisbon batch. Really excited.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Miguel Tavares</name></author><category term="bootcamp" /><category term="courses" /><summary type="html">In the following posts I will try to document my journey to becoming a developer. The main objective will be to give me a reference to what I learned and create an overview of the complete learning process. So let me start at the beginning. When did I get the idea to become a developer? For the past 5 years I have been working as a support agent for a software company called AppMachine. Working in support gave me some insight in to solving technical issues and learning to test software and find bugs. Plus it also helped me build a thick skin when dealing with angry customers! Although I enjoy working in support minus the angry customers, I started to become more curious about programming. This lead to me search for online resources to learn how to code. These are the main sites that I have used so far to learn how to code: FreeCodeCamp: very easy to get started and I liked that from the beginning you learn by solving little code challenges. The difficulty level does ramp up significantly though. In particular the projects you have to do by yourself can be hard, because you go from a guided learning process to suddenly having to build something yourself from scratch. Codecademy: best online courses I found so far. Really nice layout and well thought out learning process. I did buy the Pro version to get access to the quizzes and projects. They are currently updating the courses, so some older courses are a bit outdated. This is where I first learned Ruby. Udacity: not quite as good as Codecademy, but good to reference for specific doubts I had about HTML, CSS and JavaScript. The videos presentations are nice, but sometimes verge between funny and cringe. The Odin Project: currently I am going through this open source curriculum. Nice thing about this course is that you’re not coding in a closed environment and are forced to learn development tools from the beginning, like the command line and Git. They also reference a lot of great online resources on each subject that I’m bookmarking for later use. What’s next? The online courses really helped me make up my mind that this the path I want to pursue and gave me basic knowledge of the full development stack. Still I wanted something that would help me accelerate my learning. So after doing some research I decided… …to join the Le Wagon developer bootcamp! I will be starting at the end of September in the Lisbon batch. Really excited.</summary></entry></feed>